<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Rumyra's Head</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <id>http://rumyrashead.com/</id>
  <link href="http://rumyrashead.com/"/>
  <link href="http://rumyrashead.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Hash Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-hash-two.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-hash-two.html</id>
    <published>2017-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-04T13:17:07+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="codevember-hash-two"&gt;Codevember Hash Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's &lt;strong&gt;Sapphire&lt;/strong&gt; subject today so here's a little audio vis instead of a grid practice, as it seemed to fit a little betterer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="XzdVKJ" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember Hash 2" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/XzdVKJ/"&gt;Codevember Hash 2&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="https://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change I've made to the audio-vis software I'm building (Vizra) is to move the visuals to a canvas element to help performance. Drawing (&amp;amp; re-drawing) a butt ton of SVGs wasn't working too well. So the audio vis you'll see this Codevember are all going to be on canvas - not too much change to the actual visuals from last year. But most of work this year has been around the nuts and bolts of the software rather than the vis themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weirdly I have run into &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; performance problems recently, but that's a whole other blog post, in fact a whole series!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Hash One</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-hash-one.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-hash-one.html</id>
    <published>2017-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-02T23:28:13+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="codevember-2017"&gt;Codevember 2017&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow I almost wrote 2018 then! It's here CODEVEMBER!! ALL THE EMOJIS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tl:dr;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It's Codevember&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gonna do some CSS Grid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Probably not every day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got a book for inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will write notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven't written much this year, it's been pretty busy… I think I'll make it more of a focus next year, there's so much I want to learn and then hopefully write about. This year has very much been about sharing my thus far found knowledge. Which I will continue to do, but there's so many things which have taken a back seat and I need to sit and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is where this Codevember comes in. I need to get more practise with grid layout. I'll be teaching it in January to my bootcamp students as I'm revising my part of the course and I really want to stretch myself with it. Get it into muscle memory, and hopefully do a bit more flexbox as well. I've done a fair bit now, but I still feel like there's a lot of trial and error with both when I use them. I'm not use to this, other methods just fall off the finger tips. It'd be great to learn these inside out too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know already I can't do every day this month. I'm on a project as I write this and have 3 conferences lined up… Also I really want to buy a Nintendo Switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't worry, I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; done some more visuals this year I want to share, so expect some of them mixed in too :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="hash-1"&gt;Hash 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INSPIRATION Y'ALL :D You know how much I luv inspiration. Check out this book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/cssGridBook.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Make and Break the Grid&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I totally borrowed this from a work place years and years ago, then I forgot and then I left the job (:embarrassed_face:) but we had a googles today and you can get it for £16, so if anyone is missing it and needs reimbursing hit me up (soz).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean the title says it all really. It's got loads and loads of layouts based on different grids all the way through it. See those sticky tabs? I went through it last night and highlighted what I thought to be easy -&amp;gt; harder layouts through the use of colour. We'll see how I get on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-exercise-here-is-not-to-copy-them-directly"&gt;The exercise here is not to copy them directly…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have complete artist control, they are &lt;em&gt;inpiration&lt;/em&gt;. What I want is to practise using CSS Grid, if there's part of a layout I want to change to practise something I will most likely do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to start simple here's the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="Vrerme" data-default-tab="html,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="CSS Grid #1 : Codevember '17" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/Vrerme/"&gt;CSS Grid #1 : Codevember '17&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="https://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by this lovely image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/cssGrid1.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Simple Image Grid&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How To Be On Fire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/how-to-be-on-fire.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/how-to-be-on-fire.html</id>
    <published>2017-05-17T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-02T23:28:13+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So the other day I shared a relatively crazy experience I had in Vienna last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thankfully gettin my hair sorted out after I CAUGHT IT ON FIRE in Vienna (ask &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/csswizardry"&gt;@csswizardry&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Expect totally on fire short haired Ruth 🔥&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ruth John (@Rumyra) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rumyra/status/864100996422696960"&gt;May 15, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, thanks very much for everyone's concern and questions. I thought it probably deserved a little more explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set my hair on fire, well I say &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; it was completely by accident and totally random.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had just met up with Harry for a natter and a couple of drinks. We found a lovely bar to sit down in, ordered a couple of glasses of local viennese wine and with that Harry takes one look at me, eyes widening with what I can only describe as fear and the unfortunate words 'Ruth, I think your hair is on fire'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind my seat was a little ledge, with a little row of candles. I hadn't thought anything of it and pulled my hair up into a pony tail. But by doing so had completely endangered myself. Sure enough my hair was in fact on fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without even thinking, well ok I was thinking, I was thinking I needed to snuff the flames out, with my hand, which I infact did. But by doing so a big chunk of hair came with it, as did a ton of ash which fell all over the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor Harry. There I was still not quite sure what had happened, and here he was, with what I can only describe as a desecrated hair mess on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I wasn't injured, the flames were out and like he re-assured me throughout my paranoid mumblings through the night, 'you can't even tell'. I am 100% sure he was ready to pour a glass of water over me like a true hero!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, all is well that ends well and I visited my babe of a hairdresser yesterday. By the time I'd explained the events of the evening she had rightfully sorted out the escapade. And really I think I quite like the new hair length ☺️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class="media-feature"&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/hair.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Before and after photos of the hair fiasco&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Review</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-review.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-review.html</id>
    <published>2017-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-02T23:28:13+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wrote this back in December, then hopped in a campervan and trvelled round Australia and barely opened my laptop. It's probably still worth releasing tho&lt;/em&gt; 👉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly let's go over the last few - here's the inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="concentric-circles"&gt;Concentric Circles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/superConcen.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Concentric Circles&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="QGMyXm" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="AudioVis Codevember #16" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/QGMyXm/"&gt;AudioVis Codevember #16&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an extension of the sunburst really, it's just the shapes are being extended around rather than out. &lt;em&gt;Super&lt;/em&gt; luv this (see what I did there)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="just-circles"&gt;Just Circles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/superCircles.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Super Circles&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="ENvwMK" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="AudioVis Codevember #17" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/ENvwMK/"&gt;AudioVis Codevember #17&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems simple but you can have fun with this, lots of size and distribution fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="custom-svgs"&gt;Custom SVGs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Takashi Murakami. He's a crazy artist, I found this book at a random second hand sale at my mums old school:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/takashiCover.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Takashi Murakami book cover&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he had an exhibition when I was in London and I spot his work regularly at other exhibition. Suffice to say it's pretty awesome. Anyway super uber great for playing with a custom SVG:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/takashiScene.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Takashi Murakami scene&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="pNdmBO" data-default-tab="html,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember AudioVis #19" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/pNdmBO/"&gt;Codevember AudioVis #19&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All using the d3 technique, which I'm super enjoying for a number of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perfomance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SVGs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can also be used with Canvas and DOM elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I haven't even begun with other methods which I'm super excited about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Within the final software I just have to set some params and call a function to create the vis - this integrates really well within the eco system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="retrospective"&gt;Retrospective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="things-i-learntenjoyed"&gt;Things I learnt/enjoyed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That trying to code a pen every single day is hard - especially if you are learning new techniques &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; writing blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inspiration is cool, it gives you some boundaries. I luv making vis the sky is the limit, but this can be intimidating some times and you need a thread to start&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some d3, which makes me happy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which techniques worked the best for visuals in a browser, or rather which ones worked better than others&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It really made me think about integration into the vis software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="things-i-didntwould-do-different-next-time"&gt;Things I didn't/would do different next time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was also travelling throughout November and didn't take that into account, although I didn't think I'd hit 30 pens, I thought I would do better than 19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I really wanted to try canvas and webGL and didn't get that far&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I would load music, rather than using the mic so it would work over http, I think people are confused by the https link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually think this is the start of something. I've been meaning to release audio-vis into the wild for a while and it was a great excuse to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My VJ software Vizra has also got off the ground. There's an original hack version of the software which I've been experimenting with, performing with and generally messing around with for the past 18 months or so - but it's great to get a proper build off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="note-from-december"&gt;Note from December&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm taking a break for the rest of December - I'm in Australia for JSconfAU and will be travelling around once this is over, until Christmas. But there will be more, I can guarantee that, so just &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Rumyra"&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt; to keep up to date :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="note-from-now"&gt;Note from now&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work made a big part of my talk for JSConfAU which was actually one of my favourtie talks from last year. I've also started other work in different areas of the vis, like the analysis part started in &lt;a href="http://12devsofxmas.co.uk/2017/01/day-12-beat-dis-re-addressing-audio-analysis/"&gt;this article for 12 Devs of Xmas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically it's all go and super cool and Codevember was awesome 🕶&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Fifteen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-fifteen.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-fifteen.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-02T23:28:13+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="super-sun"&gt;Super Sun&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today's inspiration is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/superSun.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Super Sun&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today's is a little bit trickier as we have to create arc elements drawn in a circle that increase their outer arc with our data. But otherwise the code goes much the same as the previous days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry this isn't more insightful, but I am on a train on the way to the airport! Hopefully I'll be making more on the plane ✈️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="MbmwGy" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="AudioVis Codevember #15" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/MbmwGy/"&gt;AudioVis Codevember #15&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Thirteen and Fourteen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-thirfourteen.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-thirfourteen.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-02T23:28:13+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="part-three-d3js"&gt;Part Three: d3.js&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I start I want to give a big shout out to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/benjaminbenben"&gt;Ben (@benjaminbenben)&lt;/a&gt; who was helping me with some performance stuff I having trouble with. In doing so he really opened my eyes to how powerful d3 is and actually how suited a library it is to help with what we are doing here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s dubbed a ‘visualisation library’, however I think it’s relationship with data has given it a reputation that makes people who haven't discovered it, assume it’s just for pie charts. That’s changing now, and don’t get me wrong it’s good for displaying data, but that’s just it it’s good with displaying &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; it’s good with data. So anything you want to do with the DOM or anything you want to do with data and d3 has you covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed a lot of the things I’m building use a great deal of DOM manipulation and data manipulation, so it felt like a great thing to start playing with. It’s also worth noting here I’m using version 3, version 4 was recently released with a great deal of updates and changes, but as I’m learning and pretty much all the tutorials still use version 3, I’m going to stick with that. When I’m more comfortable with the library I can start to look at the update documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just have a glance down the &lt;a href="https://github.com/d3/d3/blob/master/API.md"&gt;API reference&lt;/a&gt; and we can see some totally useful data functions, array methods, thing’s for colour, layout, timing… well loads of stuff which is great for what I’m doing here. Not just with creating, but keeping and manipulating, which is easier than me writing it all out manually, and will be much better performance wise as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, ok, enough evangelising. Let’s get using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need data to get d3 to really do anything, but we have that, we have this array of velocity values from our frequency; &lt;code&gt;frequencyData&lt;/code&gt;. We can get d3 to create an element for each item in the array, attach the relative data to each element and then start to use it to manipulate the DOM element, whether that be change it’s size, position, colour of whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="number-thirteen-super-chart"&gt;Number Thirteen: Super Chart&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/superGraphic.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cover of Super Graphic book by Tim Leong&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My inspiration for this series is from the book &lt;em&gt;Super Graphic&lt;/em&gt; by Tim Leong. It's a bunch of data visualisations from and about comic books. Check it out it's pretty sweet. Perfect for inspiration for audio vis!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s start with this example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/superCharts.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Super Charts&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we have 256 items in our frequency array, piping that into d3 would mean it would create 256 elements, one for each frequency (unless we did some array manipulation, but for simplicities sake, let’s just reduce the number of elements).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s change it to less: &lt;code&gt;frequencyData = new Uint8Array(16);&lt;/code&gt; Remembering to change our fft size as well as we don't need it to be as big: &lt;code&gt;analyserNode.fftSize = 32;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all we need is a little d3 &lt;a href="https://bl.ocks.org/mbostock/3808218"&gt;“enter and exit”&lt;/a&gt; pattern. This is where we take the data and create a new element for each item, bind the data item to said element and add some params using said data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;// enter and exit
var svg = d3.select('svg');
var circle = svg.selectAll('circle'),
  radius = window.innerHeight/2.5-50;

function drawCircles() {

  requestAnimationFrame(drawCircles);
  analyserNode.getByteFrequencyData(frequencyData);

  circle = circle.data(frequencyData);
  
  circle
    .enter().append('circle')
    .attr("cy", function(d, i) {
      return Math.round(window.innerHeight/2 + (radius*Math.sin((2*i*Math.PI)/16)) );
    })
    .attr("cx", function(d, i) {
      return Math.round(window.innerWidth/2 + (radius*Math.cos((2*i*Math.PI)/16)) );
    });
  
  circle
    .attr("r", function(d) { return d/2; })
    .attr("fill", "hsla(200,50%,80%,0.7)")
    .exit().remove();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we’re creating a circle for each item in the &lt;code&gt;frequencyData&lt;/code&gt; array, then positioning them in a circle with a bit of maths. The params &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; being passed into the function are the data itself and the item number. So further below when we set the radius of the circle we can use the data, which as we know is the frequency velocity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all seems a little more succinct than how we were going about it before. In the final example I’m also creating a line, just to add a bit more 🤗&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="ENWLzK" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember AudioVis #13" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/ENWLzK/"&gt;Codevember AudioVis #13&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can already see the difference in performance compared to previous days. I’m from the "apprehensive to use a library unless I need/know etc…"" camp of JS, but in this instance it’s really helping. Most of the rest of the example are probably going to incorporate it I can imagine. So as we go through the next few days we can see what else d3 has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="number-fourteen-super-colours"&gt;Number Fourteen: Super Colours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can I say - this one is probably the most me so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="media/superColours.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Super Charts&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technique is much the same as the previous example, just this time we’re creating SVG &lt;code&gt;rect&lt;/code&gt; elements and doing some maths to position and colour them. The data is being used to adjust the brightness of the squares, although we could use it for anything. Another good example that would be good to live code at a gig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="mOWKdL" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="mOWKdL" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/mOWKdL/"&gt;mOWKdL&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
