<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Rumyra's Head</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <id>http://rumyrashead.com/</id>
  <link href="http://rumyrashead.com/"/>
  <link href="http://rumyrashead.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Nine And Ten</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-nineten.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-nineten.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-19T18:46:06+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Phew, there was a break wasn't there! Apparently it's hard to keep up when you're on the road. So I thought there's probably only one thing to do and that's try and do &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; codevembers for the next few days to make up for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's see how that goes 🤓&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="audiovis-9"&gt;AudioVis #9&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB This one comes with a warning. The way I coded this is highly UNRECOMMENDED. Not only was it a total ball ache, it doesn’t perform well and there are work arounds. It took what felt like days and the result is not amazing. If you’re wondering, I would probably use canvas for an audio vis of this nature in future. Hashtag learning, amiright?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today I’m going to expand a little on yesterday and take influence from &lt;a href="http://intothecontinuum.tumblr.com/post/119241330868/maihudson-mathematica-codesn-t-sinn3"&gt;this crazy gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in my version, I want a shape for each of the low frequencies, the mid frequencies and the high frequencies, that change depending on the level we get back from the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm setting a load more custom properties than the previous &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/yVeoJo"&gt;codevember&lt;/a&gt;, so I'm looping over them in the JS. Things I learnt include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We actually don’t need to set those properties in the root block at the top of our CSS if we’re setting them within our JavaScript. They’re set there, so they get passed into the CSS regardless… nuice!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maths in CSS is hard, even with nice things like a &lt;code&gt;calc&lt;/code&gt; function and shiny extras preprocessors like Sass give us. JavaScript is much better as maths, so I found keeping number crunching there is a lot better. Just pass the value you want in the CSS into the custom property.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="NbdXaE" data-default-tab="html,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember AudioVis #9" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/NbdXaE/"&gt;Codevember AudioVis #9&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one was a great learning experience and great experiment, even if the final result wasn't ideally what I was after at the start. I would keep using custom properties to do things like filter effects and glitch's for final VJing rather than modifying multiple DOM elements with them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="audiovis-10-blend-modes-"&gt;AudioVis #10: Blend Modes 😎&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="http://66.media.tumblr.com/cc6b92fc94e847f5358890da3ed2c5c5/tumblr_nobi29xtOO1sn5m9vo4_1280.gif" /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've actually written about using blend modes for &lt;a href="http://rumyrashead.com/a-little-thing-about-blends.html"&gt;this audio vis before&lt;/a&gt;. The make up of the visual itself isn't too different code wise to previous ones. I have some DOM elements, I am positioing them, I am animating them, the only extra feature I am encorporating is blend modes on the elements to see what effect that has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks super nice, but with all the DOM elements I have with this one performance isn't so great. I can up it by making sure I add the &lt;code&gt;will-change&lt;/code&gt; property in the CSS to any elements that have any other properties that are to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I think we should probably move into a better, more performant way of creating and manipulating DOM els for audio vis, don't you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="BQprdW" data-default-tab="html,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember AudioVis #10" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/BQprdW/"&gt;Codevember AudioVis #10&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Eight</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-eight.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-eight.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-11T23:57:44+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="part-two-random-cool-new-features"&gt;Part Two: Random Cool New Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this next section I did ponder for a while. I could take you straight on to a much better way of creating visuals within the DOM, but before I do that I want to introduce some new features we have in simple CSS that can really help our visuals later down the track. Our inspiration for this set is a little tumblr called &lt;a href="http://intothecontinuum.tumblr.com/"&gt;Archery: Into the Continuum&lt;/a&gt;. Here I want to take inspiration from some of these random gifs, not exactly replicate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So first up, this gif:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="http://67.media.tumblr.com/e829a18961367c45baf1c2dcbcea47a0/tumblr_mr6p8hVjSQ1qfjvexo2_r1_500.gif" /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id="custom-properties"&gt;Custom Properties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or&lt;/em&gt; JavaScript all up in your CSS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the much talked about CSS Custom properties. ✨💥💜 We can really use these to our advantage when doing audio vis work as we can reference them directly in our JavaScript and basically update our CSS in realtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom properties are declared at the start of your CSS with a &lt;code&gt;:root&lt;/code&gt; block and can be references throughout your CSS, much like (but not entirely) pre-processor variables. So instead of declaring properties that make sense as far as styling goes, I’m going to be changing them within my JavaScript, so it makes sense to name them something a little more explicit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this we’ll create a &lt;code&gt;—level&lt;/code&gt; property, and just grab one of the items of the &lt;code&gt;frequencyData&lt;/code&gt; array and pipe it in. This is where the magic happens:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-css"&gt;:root {
  --level: 1;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;document.documentElement.style.setProperty('--level', frequencyData[10]/255);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This —level property will now update &lt;em&gt;*within our  css*&lt;/em&gt;. Oh. My. Gawd. I know right… 😱&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we use it on the opacity for instance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-css"&gt;i {
  opacity: var(--level);
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boom! Opacity of &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; updated! In real time, in our CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know - all the wows!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="yVeoJo" data-default-tab="html,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="yVeoJo" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/yVeoJo/"&gt;yVeoJo&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Five</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-five.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-five.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-06T18:27:50+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today sees the last in our Bridget Riley series. We'll move on to something different tomorrow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is Bridget Riley's Static 4:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/media/bridgetStatic.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bridget Riley : Static 4&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This harks back to day three really, but it’s just a nice easy one. Albeit getting the circles to grow from the centre. Again nothing too special here, but it’ll look super good laid over a video I’m sure :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="yVypOR" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember AudioVis #5" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/yVypOR/"&gt;Codevember AudioVis #5&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s end on a classic: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KYSPfTMyJ2s"&gt;A to the K - Cyprus Hill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Four</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-four.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-four.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-06T00:45:52+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're in it for the long haul - so we're still using the same technique. Stick with me - come next week, I'll be looking at some different, new shiny things and the week after the same. Over the next month we shall learn some great audio vis techniques together. These ones aren't bad btw - they may just not be 'wow' juuuussstt yet 🙃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my inspiration for today’s pen: Bridget Riley's Quiver 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/media/bridgetQuiver.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bridget Riley : Quiver 3&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like this one, although it took a few tricks to get the triangles looking and positioned right. And I even didn't replicate the curved edges particularly. Later on in this series I'm going to explore different techniques and hopefully find better ways of creating shapes like these (SVGs anyone?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only big difference here is I’m jumping up the frequencies by 4 steps at a time, as there’s only 40 elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I'm only showing elements (or setting an opacity more than zero) when the frequency velocity hits over 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;if (freqVol &amp;gt; 50) {
  allRepeatedEls[i].style.opacity = freqVol/150;
} else {
  allRepeatedEls[i].style.opacity = 0;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweaked for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zN226CmaNcI"&gt;Witness the Fitness by Roots Manuva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Three</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-three.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-three.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-03T19:51:05+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my inspiration for today’s pen: Bridget Riley's Dilated Centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/media/bridgetCentres.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bridget Riley : Dilated Centers&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not be able to tell but the the circles aren’t quite concentric. The lovely &lt;a href="http://www.lottejackson.com/learning/nth-child-cicada-principle"&gt;Lotte Jackson wrote a post&lt;/a&gt; just over a month ago, about cicada, which reminded me about this piece. It used prime numbers and border radius’ to create a great ‘blobby’ effect on some images she was displaying on a website. It was a totally awesome technique, and I really wanted to try it out. What a great pen to do so with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much of the code from yesterday has changed at all apart from the DOM elements and a hec of a lot more CSS. Here I’m changing the border radius when I am looping over the &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;’s in the &lt;code&gt;animateStuff()&lt;/code&gt; function. We have more elements this time so it feels a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="BQayWP" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember AudioVis #3" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/BQayWP/"&gt;Codevember AudioVis #3&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d recommend the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1gbHItHuZ0E"&gt;opening credits to Luke Cage&lt;/a&gt; for this one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Codevember Number Two</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-two.html"/>
    <id>http://rumyrashead.com/codevember-number-two.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-02T14:10:19+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ruth John - @rumyra</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone straight for something a bit weird for day two. But we’re not doing too much different from day one. Just adding a different background gradient to the divs, displaying them with a little flex magic and again changing the widths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes these vis are simple, but I think it's good we're starting simple, stay with me and we'll see where we end!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/media/bridgetSquares.jpg" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bridget Riley : Movement in Squares&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pertinent I didn’t change much, all these little codevembers are all part of a bigger remit to add to my browser powered VJ software: Vizra. By writing a different one each day I can begin to see what functionality to include in the software. For instance a ‘live coding’ editor would be great so as I’m running the software I can change the previous days to todays whilst I’m performing. That would be a cool feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B-y-lS0YqF0"&gt;Mos Def - Ms Fat Booty&lt;/a&gt; for this one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height="300" data-theme-id="1345" data-slug-hash="PbYGNB" data-default-tab="js,result" data-user="Rumyra" data-embed-version="2" data-pen-title="Codevember AudioVis #2" class="codepen"&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/Rumyra/pen/PbYGNB/"&gt;Codevember AudioVis #2&lt;/a&gt; by Rumyra (&lt;a href="http://codepen.io/Rumyra"&gt;@Rumyra&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href="http://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://production-assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
